# **DANIEL TEEGAN**





## **PERSONAL STATEMENT**

Results-focused worker with expertise spanning from agile, scrum, CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins, infrastructure as code configuration management tools such as Ansible, infrastructure as code orchestration tools such as Terraform and containerisation tools such as Docker. Thrives working under pressure, excellent team player and will always deliver results.

## **EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS**

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.) IN PRODUCT DESIGN + 1-YEAR PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, 2018

Brighton University – Brighton and Hove, UK

Relevant course topics: market research, product ideation, product development, product launch

### BTEC LEVEL 3 EXTENDED DIPLOMA IN IT, 2014

Barnet and Southgate College – London, UK

Relevant courses: Communication and Employability Skills in IT (Merit), Computer Systems (Merit), Information systems (Distinction), Event Driven Programming (Merit), Procedural Programming (Merit), Client-Side Customisation of Web Pages (Distinction), Digital Graphics (Distinction), Computer Animation (Merit), Cisco IT Essentials Part 2 (Distinction)

### SKILLSET

- BASH Scripting
- Automation tools (Jenkins)
- Cloud computing
- Strong leadership qualities

- Creating infrastructure using Terraform
- Provisioning multiple machines using Ansible
- Agile working environment & Scrum framework
- Containerisation with Docker

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

FINNISH DEFENCE FORCES, SANTAHAMINA, HELSINKI, FINLAND, July 2018 - June 2019

#### **GUARD JAEGER REGIMENT – CORPORAL (NON-COMMISSIONED OFFICER)**

Upon completing my degree studies, I voluntarily enrolled in the Finnish military and completed the national service program.

- Completed 4 months NCO training, achieving the rank of Corporal
- Developed the ability to function peacefully and decisively in high pressure situations
- Acquired determination, leadership, discipline, flexibility and adaptability
- Facilitated all aspects of planning, problem solving, teamwork, and organization
- Guided a group of 11 privates in completing combat exercise drills and camps

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

DEVOPS TRAINING, LONDON AREA, June 2020 - September 2020

### TRAINEE DEVOPS ENGINEER

- Worked in an agile environment using frameworks such as scrum, improving work efficiency
- Competent in using version control systems such as Git
- Utilised IaaS through AWS and used Terraform to orchestrate the creation of infrastructure
- Created a CI/CD pipeline to automatically deploy code changes upon successful builds
- Provisioning multiple VMs using an Ansible playbook
- Utilising containerisation tools such as Docker

AGENCY BASED, LONDON AREA, November 2019 - May 2020

### **OPERVITIVE/SKILLED WORKER**

- Liaising with managers and contractors in regards to future duties
- Worked as an operative in a variety of site locations around the London area

Bespoke Ltd, Brighton and Hove Area, September 2016 – September 2017

## **OPERVITIVE/SKILLED WORKER (PROFESSIONAL YEAR PLACEMENT)**

- Designing aspects of the restaurant, using Solid works (CAD) software
- Installing hardware and software systems such as CCTV and payment systems

ONE LOGIC LTD, LONDON, UK, September 2013 - March 2014

### **ICT TECHNICIAN SUPPORT**

- Diagnosed and repaired computer systems and upgraded hardware/software of customers
- Installed and configured software packages to customers' specifications

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: English (Mother Tongue), Finnish

**Technical Proficiencies:** Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Creative Suite, Windows OS, Hardware &

Software.

**DevOps Tools:** Jenkins, Amazon web services (AWS), Ansible, Terraform, Docker.

Interests/Hobbies: Boxing, MMA, football, gym fitness, gaming, cooking, self-learning

technologies.